Swapnil Bhosale

3 Blu Harbor Blvd apt 230, Redwood City, California 94063 USA

□ (+1) 410-900-3119 | wyoididit@gmail.com | waspnilBhosale | waspnilBhosa

Summary_

5+ years of software development experience specializing in **back-end development, IoT, machine-learning, distributed computing, computer security**. A Researcher, programmer, and computer security enthusiastic interested in learning every day make an impact, think outside of the box, and give back to the Computer Science community.

Education_

University of Maryland Baltimore County

Maryland, USA

MASTER OF SCIENCE COMPUTER SCIENCE GPA: 3.8

Aug 2019 - Aug 2021

- Practical experience with Qubit (Qiskit) and Annealing based (D-Wave) Quantum Computing and applications.
- Quantum Computing projects involved implementing Zoom like meeting platform, virtual background Image Segmentation, and experimenting Feature Selection in machine learning for IEEE BigData 2019 Cup Suspicious Network dataset
- Researched and worked closely with Dr. Anupam Joshi for the master's thesis. Involved experimenting and extending fastText NLP technique
 using LSTM for Anomaly Detection in Windows O.S
- Worked with Dr. Anupam Joshi as a Research assistant with the Ebiquity Research Lab. Implemented a Windows Kernel Driver to tap into file, registry and network events at kernel space

University of Pune Maharashtra, India

BACHELOR OF ENGINEERING, COMPUTER ENGINEER -FIRST CLASS WITH DISTINCTION

Aug 2011 - May 2014

- Published a academic research paper on RFID based Bus Management System. Tracks buses using RFID technology, solved shortcoming of GIS, GPS system.
- Participated in various intra-college coding competitions.

Work Experience _____

Microsoft Mountain View, CA, USA

SOFTWARE ENGINEER 2 Jan. 2022 - Till date

- Lead a team of 4 member for the products around Network Virtual Appliance in the Azure Networking
- Involved in the creating architecture & design for the new features, collect requirements from product owners.
- Researching and mitigating the customer reported incident, writing a RCA documents
- Technologies: C#, Azure, Cloud, back-end

PayPal Timonium, MD, USA

SOFTWARE ENGINEER 3

- Working on the PayPal credit platform backend development activities
- Involved in the adding the new countries for the PayPal Pay Later product.
- Technologies: Java, Node JS, Docker, Spring Boot

Sky Peak Technologies

BO, CO, USA

INTERN - SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Feb. 2021 - May. 2021

Jun. 2021 - Nov 2021

- Researched and deployed an infrastructure monitoring stack using Grafana and Prometheus. Also implemented a infra interaction CLI utility using Ansible
- Developed a load and performance testing script using JMeter
- Developed functional testing suite using Cypress for browser testing
- Maintained and added support for the new REST API endpoints
- **Technologies:** Python, Java, Node JS, Docker, Kubernetes, GO lang, Shell script, Grafana, Prometheus, JMeter, Cypress, load testing

Pilot SecurityBaltimore, MD, USA

INTERN - SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Sep. 2020 - Dec. 2020

- · Devised and implemented Python library, used as a parent library for all the analysis pipeline tasks
- Implemented web Crawlers using Scrapy to download firmwares for different vendors and automate the testing
- Added a feature to read, display and export Software Bill of Materials(SBoM) for analysed firmare binary file. Worked with React JS code and added new reusable components
- Technologies: Python, Docker, Kubernetes, React-JS, GraphQL, CI/CD, Jenkins, Binary Ninja, reverse-engineering

VMware Bellevue, WA, USA

INTERN-MEMBER OF TECHNICAL STAFF

May. 2020 - Aug. 2020

• Extended AWS VM & Region support for cloud-based container life-cycle management platform. Increased business value matrix by 5%

- Reduced user waiting time by ~10 min. Developed AWS Service Quota verification back-end system for container orchestration
- Contributed to various back-end micro-services using GO-lang. Participated in poster and Hackathon competition
- Technologies: Machine Learning, AWS, Azure, server-less computing, GO-lang, Python, Docker, Kubernetes, Postgress, CI/CD, Jenkins, etc.

Pratiti Technologies Pune, MH, India SOFTWARE ENGINEER Jun. 2018 - Jul. 2019

- Lead, Contributed, & implemented new back-end micro-services in spring boot, node is & python for cloud-based IIoT platform. Took complete ownership of server-less functions (Azure and AWS) from the on-site team within ~2 weeks of knowledge transfer
- Designed & adapted Cloud Agnostic Solution for the cloud IIoT platform. Devise a solution One code for Azure, AWS, and Alibaba cloud plat-
- forms, realized using docker technology • Researched and implemented Azure API mock lib in Node JS. Value-added to company's asset and widely adopted as a mocking library for
- Azure deployed services in the company's product • Technologies: Node JS, Spring Boot, Java, Python, Typescript, MySQL, SQS, RabbitMQ, WebSockets, Docker, Jenkins, Cosmos, Dynamo DB

Xoriant Solutions pvt. ltd SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Pune, MH, India Sep. 2017 - Jun. 2018

Core member, designed, lead & implemented Software Development Kit (SDK) for the communication platform of SAP

- · Configured the CI/CD pipeline with docker and shell script to auto-configure docker images for multi-environment deployment
- Implemented Web Authentication filters/logic in API gateway(back-end service) and Nginx load-balancer using OAuth2 JWT
- · Core member of enhanced API version design, implementation, and delivery. Worked with multiple teams
- Technologies: Spring-Boot, Docker, Bamboo, Hazelcast, micro-services, Kubernetes, SAP HANA DB, Java, Nginx, JWT, OAuth, Swagger

Great Software Lab Pune, MH, India SOFTWARE ENGINEER May. 2015 - Jul. 2017

· Researched Machine Learning Model for energy optimization & deployed to pilot testing plant resulted in 25% energy savings.

- · Contributed to WebRTC and Vidyo based conferencing, webcast, webinar solutions with screen share and guest joining capability
- · Core member for Avaya Snap-In development. Adopted by the company and demoed in various VoIP conferences
- Technologies: Machine Learning, IoT, REST, VoIP, WebRTC, PHP, Python, NodeJS JQUery, Spring boot, C++, Java, Raspberry pi, HTML

Additional Contributions & Achievements

- Country to Country CTF 2020 Participant
- George Mason CTF Winner with Team CyberDawgs
- NSA CodeBreaker 2019 solved 5 problems
- Contributed to JVM implementation in Rust JVM-RS. Implemented Java Operators parsing and logic. Successfully ran toy Java program
- Implemented CHIP-8 emulator from Scratch. Had fun playing those old games again on my laptop
- Contributed to the azure-function-express NodeJS library. Implemented logging and resolved bug